# **Emmanuel Odero**

Tech Evangelist, Humanitarian & Sustainability Leader

5887 Dagoretti Nairobi ST 5887 (254)7 283-387694 emmanuelodero808@gmail.com



## **ABOUT ME**

I have a professional background in Business Information Technology, Web Design and Development passionate about Humanity, International Relations and Sustainability; My humanitarian drive has led me to work with more NGO's than IT firms; I am passionate to help organizations tap more technology to help them upscale their operations and functionalities. I have 2+ years of experience in working with NGOs, Activists and Sustainability organizations.

# **SKILLS**

Teamwork 89%	Leadership 87%	Communications 88%	Critical Thinking 91%
Management 89%	Technical Skills 90%	Illustrator 87%	Assertiveness 83%

## WORK EXPERIENCE

**Ngongroad Children's Foundation, Dagoretti -Kenya** - *Technical Assistant* June 2021 - April 2022

Ngongroad Children's Foundation is one of the most reputable and most achieving Non profit organizations/Foundations in Kenya. The organization offers full scholarships to children residing in Nairobi whose families have been impacted by HIV/AIDS.

- Website and Social media content management and updatingt.
- Data collection and sorting from fieldwork activities. Nairobi ST 5887
- •
- •
- (254)7 283-387694
- Volunteer on their Saturday program activities. Interaction with sponsored kids

# Friends Of Ngongroad, Minneapolis -USA - Technical Assistant

June 2021 - September 2021 *Roles* 

Friends of Ngong Road is the parent organization of Ngongroad Children's Foundation; it pairs each sponsor with a specific child, allowing a mutually beneficial relationship to develop.

Friends of Ngong Road helps in breaking the cycle of poverty in the slums of Nairobi, Kenya is their goal. The program is grounded in the belief that children's lives are changed when they receive an education and ultimately get a sustainable job. Through the financial support and personal encouragement of sponsors, students have the opportunity to succeed and transform their lives.

Roles

- Website and Social media content management and updatingt.
- Data collection and sorting from fieldwork activities.
- Volunteer on their Nairobi Saturday program activities.
- Interaction with sponsored kids

## Karibuloo LTD, - Web Developer

December 2021 - June 2022

Karibu loo is a leading company whose business is renting high-quality portable toilets for short term and long term sanitation needs in Nairobi. It was rated the best sanitation solution providers of the year during the Global Mice Awards. Parts of the profits in karibu loo are used to help educate children at Ngongroad Children's Foundation.

#### Roles

- Website Developer and enhancer.
- Provide technical support to its staff

# **Lidonation Foundation, -** Web Developer

December 2021 - June 2022

Lidonation is a cardano(ADA) staking pool that believes the future is for everyone. Lidonation is geared towards creating a community of change powered by blockchain technology and creating a better future for everyone. *Roles* 

• Website Development and enhancement.

**United People Global** - Deputy Captain Nairobi Change-makers Community of Champion,

Date: 06/05/022

About the Organization:

United People Global (UPG) is a community that encourages and enables people to participate in making the world a better place. This is achieved in various ways and especially by contributing to the Sustainable Development Goals (SDGs). UPG works to raise awareness, strengthen belief, facilitate collaboration and foster community. UPG uses publications, projects and events to achieve its mission.

United People Communities of Champions is a network of teams of engaged citizens to help people to make the world a better place through positive and constructive action. Each UP Community (UP Community) is a non-partisan, non-religious group within a community that is focused on empowering people to participate in the future of their communities and of our world. Nairobi Change-makers is one such group.

Roles and Achievements

-The Mentor, I am directly involved in the mentoring of about seven sustainability leaders within my community who later impactNairobi ST 5887

(254)7 283-387694 one or two others through the mentorship I give them.

- -Leadership, as a key leader in this group I have developed and learnt to effectively use the following skills; communication, being a teacher and learner all at the same time, motivator, manager and servant at the same time.
- -Able to work well with a team of different people despite gender/sexuality, religion, race, academic levels, and personal opinions.
- -Capable of designing, formulating and executing sustainable projects.

## **EDUCATION**

# Jommo Kenyatta University Of Agriculture and Technology, Nairobi

Diploma In Business Information Technology ~September 2020 - April 2021

Certificate in Business Administration ~May 2019 - December 2019

## **AWARDS & ACHIEVEMENTS**

- -Part of the youthful team that co-founded Green Legacy World (An SDG centric Startup based in Kenya and Cameroon). I was part of the ICT team that helped build their website.
- -Awarded Certificate of Distinguished contribution to the UPG community Forum
- -Certified United People Global Sustainability Champion,
- -World Bank Youth Group Delegate -2021,
- -Together with the IT team at Ngongroad Children's Foundation we were able to set up a central organization documentation software (Knowledge Base) inspired by the open-sourced Bookstackapp.

## REFEREE

Victor Wambua: victor@ngongroad.org

**Said Chesoli:** (+254)7 156 69865